Guide to the Gerald Combs papers, 1955-2001.
Combs, Gerald papers, 1955-2001.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gerald Combs papers, 1955-2001.
29-2-3335
Gerald F. Combs.
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, articles, lectures, grant material and committee work.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, articles, lectures, grant material and committee work, pertaining to Combs'career and his work with poultry nutrition, selenium and cancer.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor in Nutritional Sciences and Animal Sciences, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, articles, lectures, grant material and committee work, pertaining to Combs'career and his work with poultry nutrition, selenium and cancer.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Combs, Gerald F.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Nutritional science--Study and teaching.; Selenium--Physiological effect.; Cancer--Nutritional aspects.; Selenium--Health aspects.; Poultry--Feeding and feeds.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Conferences/ Symposiums/ Workshops/ Meetings
  - Meeting - UNICEF - India, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Symposium - Rank Prize Funds - England, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Symposium - Metal Ions in Biology and Medicine - Puerto Rico- 6th one, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Conference - Nutrition - Sweden, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Symposium - Nordic - Trace Elements in Human Health and Disease and Dresden Se Symposium, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Workshop - Chinese Agriculture, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Conference - American Institute for Cancer Research - 9th, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Symposium - Center for Legume Research, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Workshop - Agriculture - Nutrition Linkages at IRRI - Philippines, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conference - American Institute for Cancer Research (AICR), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conference - Cornell Nutrition Conference, 1998-99 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conference - International Society for Trace Element Research - France- 5th one, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Symposium - 5th International - Metal Ions in Biology and Medicine - Germany, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting - German Cancer Society - Berlin, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Symposium - Institute for Comparative and Environmental Toxicology, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conference - International Conference on Agricultural Production and Nutrition - Boston, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Conference - Food and Fitness - Oneonta, NY. - 13th one, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Symposium - on Selenium -Germany, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Conference - SLAN - Guatemala, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Council for Responsible Nutrition - California, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Symposium - Roche Technical Symposium - Illinois, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Symposium - Trace Elements in Man and Animals - Canada - 9th one, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Symposium - International Symposium on Selenium in Biology and Medicine - China, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Symposium - Food Based Approaches to Preventing Nutrient Malnutrition, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Workshop - New Approaches to RDA's Workshop - North Dakota, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Presentation - NIH/NCI - Cancer Prevention and Control - Academic Course "Micronutrients: Selenium", 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting - Delmarva Poultry Industry, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Lectures - Robert Massee Lecture and Boynton Middle School Career Day, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Conferences - Nutrition for Feed Manufacturers, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Workshop - Environmental Protection Agency - Virginia, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - International Conference on Trace Elements in Health and Disease - Sweden, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Conference - Cornell Nutrition Conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Subcommittee on Vitamin Tolerance, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Council - Infant Formula, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Meeting - Society for Environmental Geochemistry and Health - 1st one, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Conference - Colborn Feed Industry - England, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Seminar - Broiler Production, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Workshop-NSF- Grass-Fed and Grain-Fed Livestock Production Systems, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Presentations and articles by Combs, 1955-1990s (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Letter to the Editor, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - A-C, 1974-2000 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Chinese Colleagues, 1982-1994 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - CIIFAD and Cornell Institute of Food Science, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Council for Responsible Nutrition, 1980s (Box 1 1, Folder 44)
  - Degussa Corp. Trip, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - DNS and Ducoa Group, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - F-L, 1983-1998 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Hatch Projects Status, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - N, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - O, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - P, 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - R, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - S, 1974-1997 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - T, 1976-1996 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - U, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - W, 1974-1997 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - XYZ, 1975-1992 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Series III. Course Material
  - Poultry memos and articles (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Poultry Nutrition - Animal Science 415 (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
  - Problem Sets - 415 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Fundamentals of Poultry Nutrition - Animal Science 230 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Fundamentals of Poultry Nutrition - Animal Science 230, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series IV. Grants and Collaborative Projects
  - China Project - Fish Farming (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Trips to Helsinki and Taiwan, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hatch Projects, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - China Collaboration, 19984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - China Collaboration, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mead Johnson and Co. Collaboration - Studies of the Bioavailability of Selenium in Infant Formulae, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6A)
  - Grant - CSRS - Tracking Antioxidant Status in Free-Living Americans, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Grant - USDA - Dietary Selenium and Maintenance of Colonic Health, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Trip to Beijing, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Proposal to Gates Foundation, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series V. Committees - University and Others
  - Council - Animal Nutrition Research Council, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Council - Animal Nutrition Research Council, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rice Memorial Poultry Library Steering Committee, 1986-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Experimental Animal Nutrition Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Toxicology Training Program and Graduate Field at CU, 1979-1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CALS - China Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Animal Welfare Committee - CU, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Animal Utilization Reports, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series VI. Publications
  - Several reprints not listed in Combs' vita, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 19)